<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Pomodori</title>
 <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/"/>
 <updated>2009-03-19T13:16:30-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Reborg</name>
   <email>reborg@reborg.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>extracting controllers</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/19/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/19/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_6__5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 6 =&amp;gt; 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_5'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization take some time to understand how much work still to be done and fill a task list to close in 6 pomodoros 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization migrate on-pomodoro-done and on-break-done and on-app-start to the countdown-field soon to be timer-controller and update test suite for it 1 =&amp;gt; 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization summary controller to control statistics display with update-summary and format-metrics 2&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization modal button controller with on click methods for submit, void, stop and callbacks to main view to change labels 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I started to see the light of the refactoring but I still have an hard time figuring out how much work is to be done.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I should be done next session in another 8 pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;RETROSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned 6, actually done 5&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I split the modularization into multiple tasks and that worked. Underestimated heavily the timer controller work.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I was fast and fairly focused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update the clean code cheat sheet while reading the last agile in a flash card. I should have deferred this to the to-do list. The error is always the same: thinking I can do something in the 5 mins break and it takes 15 mins instead. Defer, defer, defer.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Voided again, my bad. I couldn&amp;#8217;t resist to formulate a tweet after readning on twitter and it took ages. I should consider not opening twitters each break because potentially dangerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Palomino&amp;#8217;s updates from wife, aborting. Can&amp;#8217;t really close chat in this case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  87|@planning trying to shrink refactoring to 6 pomodoros today|2009-03-19 10:20:45 -0500
  88|@planning splitted tasks for the modularization process.|2009-03-19 11:03:02 -0500
  89|@modularization moving timer related event handling from application to timer controller.|2009-03-19 11:50:38 -0500
  90|@modularization going fast but much more than a single pomo to move all behavior into the timer controller.|2009-03-19 12:21:21 -0500
  91|@modularization last pomodoro of the day. I think I did big steps but underestimated the effort. Mostly done with the new timer controller.|2009-03-19 13:08:44 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>main view work in progress</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/17/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/17/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='todays_planned_9'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_done_7'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s DONE 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;add gh-pages as submodule of master 2 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization: replace actual application.rb UI with mainview object 2 =&amp;gt; 3&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;modularization: extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='todays_not_done'&gt;TODAY&amp;#8217;s NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modularization: extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;STANDUP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to decide how big the refactoring should be and if I can call it refactoring or just a re-write of the application.rb&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I think UI modularization is more appropriate&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The work to do is to finish the layout of the mainview until I have more or less the same visual appeal of before&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Consider not to waste too much time fine tweaking the UI, try to get the modularization done first and then fine tweak the UI. The important thing is that you see everything on the UI working as before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;RETROSPECTIVE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planned 9, actually done 7&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I have to be more careful about judging how much time I have available considering one long break every 4 hours&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The refactoring operations are much more complicated than expected I should split into multiple tasks or consider if I&amp;#8217;m working on focus. Is the main view creation part of the controller extraction?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  73|@planning plus fixing some markdown jekyll generation issue|2009-03-16 15:07:24 -0500
  74|@refactor creating the main view and learning how to align layout-views correctly using the example app|2009-03-16 15:37:57 -0500
  75|@refactor creating the main-view more layout madness|2009-03-16 16:08:50 -0500
  76|@refactor creating the main view. Had to decide if to use the same label for input and output. Also had a look at NSIMage for the pomo icon|2009-03-16 16:39:49 -0500
  77|@refactor done with main-view creation copy pasting from application. It doesn't visualize as expected.|2009-03-16 17:29:42 -0500
  78|@refactor testing the new main view but having problems to see where the margin of the layouts are.|2009-03-16 18:02:54 -0500
  79|@refactor did some progress on understanding layouts. The mode vertical/horizontal for example. Still fighting for the best layout.|2009-03-16 18:36:55 -0500
  80|@website finally got gh-pages as master submodule so I can change the site from the master branch|2009-03-17 08:43:32 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>some refactoring</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/16/todo.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/16/todo</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id='today_planned_9'&gt;TODAY PLANNED 9&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;refact extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb 4&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;charts Add a feature to the pomodoro model so that &amp;#8216;something&amp;#8217; in the description is automatically collected as tag internally 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='today_done'&gt;TODAY DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning 1 =&amp;gt; 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='today_not_done'&gt;TODAY NOT DONE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refact extract multiple controllers and new mainview object from application.rb. 4 =&amp;gt; 7&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;charts Add a feature to the pomodoro model so that &amp;#8216;something&amp;#8217; in the description is automatically collected as tag internally. 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='internal_interruptions'&gt;INTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='external_interruptions'&gt;EXTERNAL INTERRUPTIONS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='relevant_history'&gt;RELEVANT HISTORY&lt;/h2&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>work on charts started</title>
   <link href="http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/13/charts.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://reborg.github.com/pomodori/2009/03/13/charts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just realized that this brain dump and retrospective I was writing at the end of each planning page for the day is a perfect fit for the content of this micro blog! The retrospective is process only: how my PT (Pomodoro Technique) is doing, pros and cons, what went right and what went wrong. The standup is to get started for the day: yesterday&amp;#8217;s achievements, today&amp;#8217;s plan, design ideas and so on. Everyday is taking me 1 pomodoro for this and definitely worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='retrospective'&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still shooting for half a day of work these days, that means around 8 pomodoros.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Productive morning no internal/external interruptions.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t forget about the longer break this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='standup'&gt;Standup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now a button that opens a new window with a webview that shows just a static HTML. The next step is of course to connect that HTML generation to the pomodoro history.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I need a component that starting from a template is able to generate the HTML table with correct numbers to host the current pomodoros worked by tags chart.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I also started thinking about refactoring the appliction.rb main file into multiple controllers, one for each part of the UI.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I found the following architectural rule to be consistent: one class per view that represents only the UI tree and nothing else. One controller for each sub-view (this is because a sub-view is really an independent user story on its own). The controller can use zero or more model objects. There are controllers with no back end model. The controller works as a presenter: the controller knows about views and model and send command to change the view when the model change.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I tried choctop: it doesn&amp;#8217;t work without an underlying Xcode project, or at least not the tutorial. It&amp;#8217;s a framework, so I suppose it can be used also with macruby. But I don&amp;#8217;t know how and now it&amp;#8217;s too complex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='raw_dump'&gt;RAW DUMP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
69|@planning realized I can use the blog feature of gh-pages as a daily plan page, retrospective and the rest.|2009-03-13 09:16:42 -0500
70|@mvp started refactoring by extracting void pomodoro function|2009-03-13 09:55:06 -0500
71|@refact extended pomodoro_controller to call the view and started a new main_view to remove everything UI related from application.rb|2009-03-13 11:03:19 -0500
72|@project migrated to 0.4 now playing again with view_layout expansion to remove abolute widgets locations.|2009-03-13 11:34:30 -0500
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>